Creamy Cilantro Chipotle Chicken. 40 min · 4 servings · Mexican
Ingredients: 12. 4 boneless skinless chicken breasts (about 1 pound), about 1/2-inch thick; Salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste; 2 tablespoons oli…
Step 1. Pound chicken breasts to about a 1/2-inch thickness, then season with salt and pepper.
Step 2. Heat 1 1/2 tablespoons olive oil in a large skillet over medium-high heat.
Step 3. Add chicken to the hot oil and cook for 5 to 6 minutes per side, or until cooked through and no longer pink. Use an Instant Read Thermometer; chicken…
Step 4. Set skillet back over medium-high heat and add the remaining oil.
Step 5. Stir in chopped shallots and garlic; cook for 1 minute.
Step 6. Gradually add chicken broth; stir and scrape up all the browned bits from the bottom of the skillet.
Step 7. Bring mixture to a boil; continue to boil gently for 10 minutes, or until liquid is reduced to about 1/3 cup.
Step 8. Reduce heat to medium and whisk in the heavy cream.
Step 9. Add butter a few cubes at a time, stirring after every addition until butter melts.
Step 10. Stir in 1 tablespoon chopped fresh cilantro, chopped chile pepper, and adobo sauce.
Step 11. Taste the sauce for salt and pepper, and adjust accordingly.
Step 12. Add the chicken back into the pan; cook for 1 minute, or just enough to heat through.
You're ready. Use Make It for checkboxes on the page.